## NETWORK ENGINEER IV

Professional Summary

Experience over the last 20 years has included working many aspects of the IT environments, which ranged from workstation and A server setup and support to network infrastructure, architecture, installation, and maintenance. The last eight years have been spent focusing on Cisco and F5 hardware and software support which included using SolarWinds to monitor the equipment. Software support has focused on the following software from Cicso: ISE, ACS, Cisco Works, and WCS. Most recently have worked on NERC compliance related to the IP network and change control.

Skills

Detailed IP Network Design

IP subnetting

Packet Capture decoding

Leadership of several network engineers on several projects

Develop hardware materials lists Â Â Â

Develop procedure documents

Connected Grid Switch 2010 Connected Grid Router 2520

F5 GTM and LTM

Work History

Network Engineer IV, 08/2006 to Current

Multiplan Inc. – Bedford, MA

Troubleshooting various IP network issues in layers 1 through 3 of the OSI model

Communication with team member and customers

Problem Solving

Develop Network Drawings using Visio NERC CIP compliance experience

Cisco ASA

Cisco IOS Firewall feature set

Cisco Catalyst 6500, 4500, 3850, 3750, 3560, 2960 switches Cisco Routers 7200, 2900, 2800, 1800 Cisco Wireless Controllers 4400, 5500 Cisco Access Points 1100, 1200 Cisco Wireless Bridge 1300

- Currently leading network engineers working to operate around 600 devices at over 100 locations across Kansas and MissouriÂ
- Currently leading multiple engineers in multiple projects dealing with Cisco router and switch installations as well as F5 configurations
- Led a project to install Nexus equipment in the data center to provide 10Gb connectivity for end devicesÂ
- Led the project to replace Cisco CSS devices with F5 LTM and GTM devices
- Worked in lead role to redesign the IP network to support the requirements for the Land Mobile Radio System IP network backhaul
- Led large pilot project for Smart Grid demonstrations at KCP&L which included implementation of Cisco Connected Grid routers and switches, DMVPN and Point to Point VPN configurations
- Led a project to install Cisco NAC at the Head Quarters building
- · Worked to help design and implement new data wiring and cable management standards
- Replaced of end-of-life Cisco equipment with updated network equipment at various KCP&L locations
- Extended IOS experience with several device types
- Routing experience with EIGRP, OSPF, and BGP
- Helped to develop procedures to comply with NERC CIP regulations

System Analyst III, 08/2001 to 08/2006

Alaskausa Mortgage Company â€" Hesperia, CA

- Supported Microsoft Windows Operating System on servers and desktops
- Operating systems included NT 4.0, 2000 and 2003 Server, and XP
- Maintained Dell and Compaq/HP hardware
- Administered backups using Veritas Netbackup Data Center to large HP tape library
- Helped implement various new software applications
- Supported web servers for intranet and internet sites
- Supported File and Print servers and various application servers running MS SQL server, Pervasive SQL, and Weblogic

Network Engineer, 03/2000 to 08/2001

Aircell â€" Broomfield, CO

- Implemented and supported Network monitoring applications for the internal corporate network
- Used Sun servers running Solaris 2.6 and 2.7
- Managed the Cisco routers and various servers with real-time monitoring tools including Cisco Works and Tivoli NetView
- Maintained DNS and DHCP servers running QIP software from Lucent

System Analyst, 03/1996 to 03/1999

Fiserv â€" Wilmington, DE

- Supported 10-20servers and 50-100 clients in the Corporate Security department
- Moved from Netware and Windows 3.11 to NT 4.0 workstation and Server
- Moved from token-ring to switched Ethernet using Cisco switches and routers
- After the migrations were complete helped move the equipment to a new location
- At the new location brought up T-1's connected to Cisco hardware
- Later helped deploy a Windows 2000 web hosting environment

Engineer/Analyst, 05/1993 to 03/1996 Linquest Corporation â€" Augusta, GA

- Installed network cable and hubs for a new network infrastructure
- The workstations used Windows 3.1 with PC-NFS on TCP/IP
- This provided file and printer sharing for draftsmen, engineers and secretaries

## Education

Bachelors of Arts: Theology, Heartland Bible College - City, State

## Theology

1997 - Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer +Internet Â Â Â Â Â

2007 - CCNA Boot Camp Â Â Â Â Â

2012 - BGP Training Â Â Â Â Â

2012 - MPLS Training Â Â Â Â Â

2013 - Nexus Training Â Â Â Â Â

2014 - F5 GTM Training Â Â Â Â

2014 - CCNA Certification Â Â Â Â

2014 - UCS Training

## Skills

BGP, cable, CCNA, Cisco, Cisco routers, Cisco router, Cisco Works, Compaq, hardware, CSS, clients, Dell, desktops, DHCP, DNS, EIGRP, Ethernet, HP, hubs, Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer, Microsoft Windows, Windows 2000, 2000, Windows 3.1, Windows 3.11, NT 4.0, NetView, Network, Netware, Operating systems, Operating System, OSPF, PC-NFS, Print servers, printer, real-time, routers, Routing, servers, Solaris 2.6, MS SQL server, SQL, Sun servers, switches, switch, Cisco switches, T-1, TCP/IP, Tivoli, token-ring, Veritas Netbackup, VPN, web hosting, web servers, Weblogic, NT 4.0 workstation, wiring